Email: david.j.bramwell@googlemail.com

Website: https://dbramwell.github.io/

### DAVID BRAMLER

# Summary

A seasoned lead software engineer with a professional background in all aspects of the software delivery lifecycle, having had roles in development, operations and testing. A strong communicator and collaborator with experience leading delivery teams and mentoring less experienced team members.

Passionate about software and tech in general, my free time often includes coding and I like to contribute to open source. A list of my open source contributions can be found at <a href="https://dbramwell.github.io">https://dbramwell.github.io</a>.

# **Previous Employment**

### **Sponge - Senior Software Developer**

September 2020 - Current

Python, Django, VUE js, Terraform, Kubernetes, GCP, CDK, AWS, Docker, Github Actions, PSQL, pyte

Lead developer of Sponge's flagship Learning Management System (LMS). Written using Django and Vue, and deployed to a mix of services across GCP and AWS.

#### Responsibilities:

- Liaising with product owners around new features.
- Leading the team in agile ceremonies, making technical decisions while breaking down new features into small deliverables that could be split across the team.
- Creating and refining our delivery pipelines.
- Championing the importance of tackling technical debt and automated testing.
- Exploring new tech and laying the groundwork when introducing new pieces of tech, such as new api, frontend and test frameworks.

#### Endemol Shine Group - Full Stack Developer/Technical Lead

June 2018 - September 2020

Javascript, Typescript, ReactJS, PHP, AWS, CDK, Amplify, Cypress, FFMPEG, MYSQL, Docker

Lead developer of a Training Platform as well as a key developer on Endemol's Media Asset Management (MAM) system, both of which utilized a large number of serverless and server based AWS services. I held responsibility for key architecture decisions and mentored newer members of the team. I also instilled best practices such as code reviews, automated testing and infrastructure as code into the development lifecycle of all applications.

#### **Comprehensive Care - Full Stack Developer**

6 month contract in New Zealand while on a 2 year backpacking trip

June 2017 - December 2017

Javascript, Ruby on Rails, Angularjs, Jenkins, MS SQL

Lead developer of an asthma treatment recommendation application, built on Rails and Angularjs. Ran workgroups on best practices and championed addition of unit tests and automated deployments across all applications.

#### **UBS Investment Bank - Developer**

February 2016 - July 2016

Javascript, BackboneJS, Grails, Java, Groovy, Gradle, Maven, Teamcity, Oracle SQL

Working in a cross-functional scrum team of 6, across a suite of 10 Java applications and 1 Grails application as well as maintaining and improving the CI pipeline. All our work was done following agile processes with two week sprints, regular backlog grooming and utilising TDD.

#### **UBS Investment Bank - Dev-Ops Engineer**

**April 2013 - February 2016** 

Gradle, Maven, Java, Groovy, Teamcity, Bash, RHEL, Javascript, Oracle SQL

Part of a 5 person team responsible for providing developer enablement for around 80 developers and automating the build and deployment processes of 10 applications.

### Betfair - QA automation engineer

**November 2011 - March 2013** 

Groovy, Java, Selenium Webdriver, Maven, Jenkins

Responsible for automating the manual test library.

### Qualifications

- BSC Degree in Mathematics from Nottingham University
- A-Levels:
  - Maths A
  - Further Maths A
  - Chemistry C
- GCSEs: 11 A\* to C